Hello friends, I am your friend Vivek
Pawar, I welcome you
to the YouTube channel of policyplan.com. Workman
Compensation means insurance for loss compensation or
you can call it labor insurance. So,
you are going to get complete information about Workman Compensation Insurance in this video. It is
very important information.
Very few videos are available in this section.
So stay tuned till the end of this video, it can be
very beneficial for you.
Friends, let us know what the Workman Compensation policy basically is.
See, there is a
leader, there is an employee, there is a worker. Okay, so there is a
difference between worker and employment. So, the Workman
Compensation policy is
for the workers. So, friends, whenever people hire such
contractors, wherever we
go, okay, or there is any contractor
who is hiring workers,
foreign examples, we will tell you one or two examples
here like ICC contractor,
painting contractor, electrical
contractor, okay, so these are the contractors, they take care of the
entire electrical work on a 12-storey building.  If he is working then
he needs what he needs, a
comparison, so
what will the people who will work at his place do, the workers will work, the
workers will stay, okay, so let's say
he has 15 people working, so you should know
friends, no one here is permanent, the
relief worker is given A B
C today, tomorrow he can be X A C, okay, so
it's an N name policy, in this policy
their names are not mentioned with the labour, you don't have to give the name,
you don't have to tell how many
workers are working, so friends,
what does the labour doctor say about this, that
your worker, that is, the worker, works
on the trust of his owner, that is, I am
telling you in layman's language, so
whatever loss he has to bear if any
accident happens to him, okay, whatever his damage is, that is, the one to whom the compensation has to be given, that is,
his
compensation has to be given, okay, that is, there is a bodily injury,
hospitalization or death or there is
permanent disability or there is
parcel disability, any of this happens
while working  So it is
very important for him to get compensation, friends,
he can take it from his employer, he can
take it from the insurance company, but he must get it.
This is what the labor court says.
In every step, the labor doctor works in different ways,
so his practice is also different,
but if
someone does not have a broad compensation policy,
if he is a contractor, then you should know one thing,
friends, he does not get compensation there nowadays. Okay, suppose there is
a big builder, a
professional builder, where he has to pay compensation to the
contractors, then
first he has to say, show me your compensation
policy which is live, how many
workers are written there, show me that policy and
start your work. Otherwise, you are
not even given the opportunity to start your work. So it is
basically compulsory insurance, so friends,
if someone wants to take a compensation policy, then
basically how does one get its code first,
what information is required for it,
if someone wants to get a quotation first, how much
premium is going to be charged, then for that we will have to
give him the name of the company, okay, like
XAS  Enterprises is the name of the company, if it has a
proprietor, if it is a partnership, then
their names. If the company is a partnership, then the
GST number of the form will have to be given. If the form is
proprietary, meaning the owner is the sole owner, then the
PAN number of the owner, his
address, will have to be given. After that,
what type of work is it, at what height? For
example, someone is a painting contractor
and he is going to work on a building of about 10 sq ft.
This policy is taken, but
you have to tell about Pune purpose and Maharashtra, the whole India location will be
added in the policy. The
policy is divided for multiple locations as well, there are
policies for single location as well. How many
workers work indirectly at your place?
You have to tell the figure of the highest number of workers. For example,
if I have 10 workers working, then it is
important to tell me at least friends, what do people do, to
save the premium, they tell a lower figure. For example, I have
10 people working
and I have taken out insurance for two-three people.
If an accident happens and I have taken out
insurance on my own, then there will be a problem in the claim.
Friends, it is
very important to take out insurance policies for the number of workers who actually work for you.
If there is a debt claim, it will be
passed in the labor court.
How much is the amount of wages due, how much was
he going to earn, there is a
multiplication factor according to that, which is calculated and
set by the company through the
labor court and the insurance company.
If you take out insurance, then the
insurance company will pay your labor claim.
If you do not take out insurance, then the
contractor or the
builder or the owner will have to pay that money.
Everyone will have to pay together,
but it will not have to be paid, friends, the
labor will have to pay the compensation. This is the labor
doctor. So, after giving complete information,
only the policy is distributed after the general insurance company. There is
no life insurance or
health insurance. General insurance means
ICC, Lombard General, Bajaj, Allianz General,
Tata General Insurance. All the general
insurance companies have work policies
available very easily. So,
if you ask which company is good, then the one whose claim
settlement is very fast.  It is very important to get a policy from those who are experts in this, who have
taken out a lot of policies. One
who does not know anything about this policy should
not get a policy from someone who does not know anything about this policy.
Friends, so those are insurance brokers. We have a
lot of claims from this company. We are
experts in this. We have
also made many claims in this regard. Friends,
you have to go to the experts.
So,
come to policyplanner.com. We will give you the best code for this. You will find the best
company and guarantee the claim.
Friends, after filling in the complete information of the genuine clip
workman compensation policy, the
policy
document can be found online.
You can make the payment online only.
If someone takes
out a policy and some accident happens while working, then
you may have to bear a huge loss.
Whenever an accident happens,
how does the police act? So, if you do not have a policy,
if you have not followed the safety elements, if you have
not followed the safety parameters, then there is a possibility of serious
action against you. So, do
not forget to get this policy.
Friends, whoever works in contractual work,
Friends, let us know some more things
in this, if an accident happens then it should happen while working,
after work the worker is going home
and if something happens then you will
not get tax, only in case of
giving it on duty, only the
claim bill is going to happen, so see
friends, there can be a death claim as well, you can
also get a claim for disability, that is
partial disability, total permanent
disability or temporary disability and if
you have taken an
accidental hospitalization then you can get
hospitalization tax in that too,
up to 50000, you can also get one article, you can get a claim
twice or thrice in a year in one policy,
okay what is required for this,
when I am a contractor then it is
necessary for me to have his presentation book, if any person meets with an accident
then his name must be in that book,
he must have an ID card provided by me
and if he is driving then
he must wear a helmet, he
must wear a belt, after that there must
be a net there too, which is then the
relief which is called Panchnama  They say the police
also play a big role here,
if we do not follow any safety parameters then there is a
possibility of your claim getting rejected, okay so what is it friends, first of all it is
necessary to take out a policy, after that it is
necessary to maintain the records and thirdly it is
necessary to follow all the safety parameters,
okay friends, if you have any such
big claims then also we will
support you, even if you have
not taken out a policy from us, but
you will definitely get help from us in the claim,
friends,
in the claim of workman compensation, we have a good
expert team who can help you a lot,
so you should go with the policy plan
where you will get immediate policy,
immediate court and immediate
and better service
role for the claim, so if you liked the information then
definitely like us, share it, do
not forget to subscribe to the channel and
share this video with your friends,
friends, whatever comments you give, welcome,
so see you in the next video, friends, thank you
for giving your time, thank you